interac.ca 2019-12-10

# Interac - Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy describes how Interac Association, Interac Inc. and Acxsys Corporation (collectively " **we** " or " **us** ") collect, use and disclose personal information transmitted by visitors to our website located at www.interac.ca, and users of the Acxsys Innovation Hub (“Hub”) located at developer.interac.ca, and the online and mobile versions, (referred to together as our “ **sites** ”) and from individuals with whom we deal offline (" **you** " or " **your** ").

### Consent

This Privacy Policy outlines what personal information is collected and why and how it is used and disclosed.

By visiting our sites and/or by providing us with your personal information, you consent to our collection, use and disclosure of your personal information for the purpose for which it was collected, as described in this Privacy Policy, as amended from time to time, or as identified by us to you at the time of collection. If you do not wish to have your personal information collected, used or disclosed in this manner, then please either (1) do not use our sites and/or submit your personal information to us, or (2) exercise opt-out procedures described herein or that may be offered at the time of collection. Please note that while you may opt-out or withdraw consent to the collection, use or disclosure of your personal information to us, as a result, you may no longer be able to use features of the sites upon which such information depends.

Subject to any legal restrictions and reasonable notice, you may withdraw your consent to our retention, use or disclosure of your personal information by contacting us at the address provided below.

Where permitted by law, we may infer your consent to collect, use or disclose your personal information. We may collect, use or disclose your personal information without your knowledge or consent where permitted or   
required by law.

### How We Use And Disclose Your Personal Information

We only use the personal information you provide to us for the purposes for which it was provided.

If you send us a query, we will collect your personal information to establish your identity and respond to your questions, comments or concerns or take other actions in response to your query. If you advise us that your query relates to a particular Interac Association member or a participant in Acxsys Corporation’s services we may, unless you instruct otherwise, disclose your personal information you provide to us to that organization so that it may respond to you directly. Please do not include any of your banking or other financial information in your communications with us.

If you are a user of the Hub, we may collect your personal information in order to provide access to the Hub, operate the user forum and facilitate management of users’ accounts (e.g. collection of a user’s name and e-mail address in order to allow us to create a login and password for the Hub).

We consider your personal information confidential and we do not sell it to others. We may disclose your personal information to our third party service providers, provided that the applicable third parties are bound by an agreement to protect such information and only use it in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you choose to receive them, we may periodically send you email messages describing updates, new features, or promotional offers related to our sites and services/products. You can choose to stop receiving this email at any time. Simply follow the instructions included in your email, or send a reply stating your request. If you do not explicitly choose to receive informational emails, the only email messages you will receive from us will be to respond to email inquiries that you send us.

### Use of 'Cookies'

We make use of cookie technology to track user patterns on our sites and allow the user to remain logged in after rebooting. A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that identifies your browser but not you to our computer each time you visit. We may also use Internet tags, graphic tags and similar web beacon type functions for the same purpose. Like cookies, they do not collect your personal information.

You will find that most major websites use cookies and most major browsers are set up to accept them. You do not need cookies to visit our sites. However, if you refuse to accept cookies, you may not be able to use some of the features available on our sites.

We also use Google Analytics for user level tracking and you are subject to their privacy policy, which is located at [http://google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html](http://google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html).

### Sites Aggregate Data

Our sites automatically collect certain information from visitors to our sites, namely IP addresses, information regarding the type of Internet browser and operating system used, and the domain name of the website or advertisement from which the visitors have linked to our sites (if applicable). If you choose to register for the Hub, you may be asked to provide optional information such as the name of the business you work for and/or the industry you work in. We render all of this information anonymous and retain it in aggregate form to measure interest in the Hub, usage of the sites, including but not limited to the total number of visits, average time spent on the sites, and pages viewed, both in real-time, and within a certain historical time frame. We use this aggregated information to improve the utility, security, content and user   
experience of our sites.

### Retention Of Personal Information

Information we collect from visitors to our sites is rendered anonymous and retained only in aggregate form for the purpose of statistical analysis.

We will destroy, erase or render anonymous personal information no longer required for the purpose(s) for which it was collected, subject to any legal or business requirement to retain it.

### Security Safeguards

We take precautions to protect your personal information against unauthorized access, disclosure, inappropriate alteration, and misuse. Access to your personal information is restricted to those individuals whose job responsibilities require them to have access. The precautions taken to protect your personal information include physical, organizational, and technological measures. However, given that electronically transmitted data is not 100% secure, we make no warranties as to the security of any information that you submit to us electronically, which you do at your own risk.

You also play a valuable part in security. After you have finished using our sites, you should log out and exit your browser to prevent unauthorized users from returning to your online session. If you are accessing our mobile site, you should ensure that your device’s privacy settings are set in accordance with your privacy preferences. If you believe that someone has improperly used or provided information about you that you did not authorize, please contact us immediately in one of the ways provided below.

### Other Websites

Our sites contain links to other websites owned and operated by third parties. The third parties who operate these websites may treat the collection, use and disclosure of personal information differently than we do. This could be the case even for those websites that carry our trade-marks or logos or which may be framed by our sites. We therefore encourage you to review the privacy policies of these websites before disclosing your personal information to any third party. We are not responsible for the collection, use and disclosure practices of companies or organizations to which our sites may provide links.

### How To Access Or Correct Your Personal Information

In order to respond to your inquiries, we will establish and maintain a file of the personal information that you provide to us. Your file will be kept by us at the address provided below. Only our employees or agents who need to access your file in the course of their duties will have access to your file.

If you wish to request access to, or correction of, your personal information held by us, please write to our Chief Privacy Officer using the contact information provided below. Some information may not be accessed in certain circumstances, for example if it contains personal information of other persons or for legal reasons. To protect your privacy, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you access to, or making corrections to, your personal information.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time and will post the latest version on our sites in a timely manner. We recommend that you review this Privacy Policy periodically so that you are aware of any changes. Your continued use of our sites constitutes your acceptance of such changes.

### Contact For Further Information

If you have any inquiries, requests or complaints regarding this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, please contact our Chief Privacy Officer at:

**Interac Association/Acxsys Corporation**

Attention: Chief Privacy Officer

Royal Bank Plaza, North Tower

200 Bay Street, Suite 2400

P.O. Box 45, Toronto, ON

M5J 2J1

privacy@interac.ca

This Privacy Policy was last updated on October 6, 2016.
